これより ハンター試験を開始いたします。
The Hunter Exam will now begin!
私　１次試験官の サトツと申します。
I am Satotz, the Phase One examiner.
２次試験会場まで 私に　ついて来ること。
You must follow me to Phase Two.
それが　１次試験でございます。
This is the exam's First Phase.
試験開始から２時間
Two hours have passed since
the start of the exam.
受験者達が走った距離は
The applicants have traveled
スタートから ３０ｋｍを超えていた
over thirty kilometers from the start.
トータルで 何ｋｍ走るか分からない
None of them knows how far they must go.
ゴールを 知らされていない上で走る ペース配分
They are forced to run at the leader's pace,
with no goal specified.
先の見えない単調なコースが
It's a monotonous course with no end in sight.
数名の脱落者を出し始めていた
And many applicants have
already dropped out.
過去のデータから このパターンの試験は
Extrapolating from historical data,
this exam type usually
ズバリ　４０ｋｍのコース！
involves a forty-kilometer course.
僕の計算では　そろそろ ゴールが近いですよ！
My calculations suggest that we are nearing the goal...
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。 ナメてたぜ ハンター試験を…
I underestimated the Hunter Exam.
こいつら　みんな化け物だ 化け物の集まりなんだな
Every person here is a monster. It's a gathering of monsters...
こら待て！　ガキ！ ん？
Hey! Wait up, kid! Hmm?
てめぇ　ハンター試験 ナメんじゃねえぞ！
You should show the
Hunter Exam some respect!
何のこと？
What do you mean?
「何の」って　そのスケボー！ 反則だろ！
Why are you using a skateboard? That's cheating!
何で？
Why?
なっ… これは持久力のテストなんだぞ！
Why... This is an endurance test!
違うよ。 はぁ？
No, it isn't. Huh?
ゴン　てめぇ　何いってる！
Gon, what are you saying?
試験官は　「ついて来い」って いっただけだもんね。
The examiner only told us to follow him.
てめぇ　どっちの味方だ！　あぁ？
Whose side are you on, eh?
ねぇ　君　いくつ？ １２歳。
Hey, how old are you? I'm twelve years old.
ふん　同い年ね
Hmm... We're the same age.
ん？
Huh?
やっぱ俺も　走ろうっと！
Guess I'll run too.
おぉ　カッコいい！
Wow! That was cool!
俺　キルア。 俺は　ゴン！
I'm Killua. I'm Gon.
クッソ　ふざけやがってぇ…
Damn it... Making a fool out of me...
僕の計算に狂いは　ない！
It's impossible! My calculations are never wrong!
じゃあ　なぜ…
So why...
ひょっとして　このまま脱落？
Am I... going to fail?
この僕が脱落？ ウソだ…　あり得ない！
For me to fail... That's absurd. Unthinkable!
そんなのイヤだ！
I won't accept that!
あっ　うぅ…。 ヘイ　ルーキー！
Hey, rookie!
だらしねえぞ　坊や！
You're a mess.
こんな所で　へばる奴 かなり珍しいぜ。
It's rare to see someone
out of steam so early.
表彰もんのヘタレ野郎だぜ てめぇはよ。
You must be a hell of an incompetent.
ハンター試験でも お前のような奴は 落ちこぼれってんだ。
People like you are doomed
to fail the Hunter Exam.
二度と来んな　クズ野郎！
So don't come back, snotrag!
あぁ!!
Here. Thanks.
あんだけ　ボロクソにいっときゃ もう立ち上がれねえだろ！
He won't recover from the abuse
we just dished out.
ありゃ　二度と ハンター試験は受けねえな！
I doubt he'll ever take the
Hunter Exam again.
にしても　トンパよ
Anyway, Tonpa...
お前　ホントに ルーキー潰しが好きだな。
You really do love crushing rookies.
フン… それが　俺の生きがいだからな。
I live for it.
すでに６０ｋｍくらいは 走っただろうか
We must have traveled at least sixty kilometers.
一体　いつまで走ればいいんだ
How much farther do we need to go?
ハンター試験で ルーキーが合格する確率は ３年に１人
Only one rookie, every three years,
passes the Hunter Exam.
俺みたいな凡人には 夢のまた夢ってわけだ…
So for a normal human like me, it isn't even worth dreaming about...
クソっ
Damn it.
おい　ほっとけよ　早く行こうぜ。
Hey, forget him. Let's get going.
ざけんなよ！
Screw that...
絶対ハンターに なったるんじゃ!!
I'm gonna become a Hunter!
クソったらぁ!!
Damn it all!
カッコいい！
Cool!
後で俺にも　やらせてよ。
Let me try that later.
スケボー貸してくれたらね！
If you let me try your skateboard, okay?
８０ｋｍ地点を通過しました
We've reached the eighty-kilometer mark.
さて ちょっとペースを上げますよ
It is now time to pick up the pace a bit.
おいおい　マジか？
Wait, are you serious?
何て奴だ 普通に歩くような感じで 楽々と上って行きやがる。
That guy's insane. He's prancing up the stairs,
as if they're not even there.
このペースじゃ かなりの脱落者が出るぜ。
If he keeps up this pace, tons of people will fail.
ゴン　どっちが先にゴールするか 競走しないか？
Gon, wanna race to see who finishes first?
いいよ！　勝ったほうが ごはん１回おごりね！
Sure. The loser has to buy dinner.
よし　乗った！
Okay, you're on!
よい　ドン！ よい　ドン！
Ready... Go!
レオリオ　大丈夫か？
Leorio, are you okay?
おうよ！　見ての通りだぜ！
Sure! Just look at me.
なりふり構わなきゃ　まだまだ 行けることが分かったからな！
I realized that I can keep going if I don't worry about how stupid I look!
フフっ　私も少しは 奴を見習うか
I should probably follow his example.
ふっ！　ふっ！　ふっ！ ふっ！　はっ！　ほっ！
Leorio...
レオリオ　１つ　聞いていいか？
I have a question.
何だ 随分　余裕じゃねえか　クラピカ。
What? Is this too easy for you, Kurapika?
無駄口は　体力消耗するぜ！
Talking just wastes energy!
ハンターになりたいのは 本当に金が目当てか？
Are you really trying to become
a Hunter for the money?
違うな　ほんの数日の付き合いだが それくらいは　分かる。
You aren't, right? We've only been together for a few days, but I know you better than that.
確かに　お前の態度は軽薄で 頭も悪い。
Sure, you have a nasty attitude,
and you aren't very bright.
ムキっ！ だが　決して 底が浅いとは思わない。
But you're not a shallow person.
金儲けだけが生きがいの人間は 何人も見て来たが
I've seen many who live for money.
お前は　そいつらとは違う。
You're nothing like them.
へっ！　へっ！　ふっ！
You and your logic...
「緋の目」。
Scarlet eyes.
それが クルタ族が襲われた理由だ。
That's why the Kurta were targeted.
「緋の目」とは クルタ族特有の特殊体質…。
We Kurta are known for
our unique scarlet eyes.
感情が激しく高ぶると 瞳が燃えるような 深い緋色になるんだ。
When our emotions are heightened, our eyes turn scarlet, as though on fire.
その緋色の輝きは
The eyes in that scarlet state
世界７大美色の１つに 数えられるほどで
are considered one of the seven most
beautiful colors in the world.
ブラックマーケットで 高額で取引される。
They command high prices
on the black market.
それで「幻影旅団」に 襲われたわけか。
That's why the Phantom Troupe
attacked you?
打ち捨てられた 同胞の亡きがらからは １つ残らず 目が奪い去られていた。
They took every single eye from
my brethren's corpses.
今でも　彼らの暗い瞳が 無念だと語りかけて来る。
I can still hear their darkened eyes
crying out in anguish...
私は　必ず「幻影旅団」を 捕らえてみせる！
I swear I will capture the Phantom Troupe!
そして　仲間達の目を 全て取り戻すんだ！
And I will reclaim the eyes of my clan!
それでハンターに。
That's why you want to be a Hunter?
ああ　金持ちの 契約ハンターになれば ブラックマーケットの　さまざまな情報を 聞き出せるからな。
Yeah, if I become a Hunter with rich clients, I'll gain access to black market information.
だが　そいつは お前さんが最も嫌う
But you'll have to swallow your pride
誇りを捨てた「飼い犬ハンター」に なるってことだぜ。
and become the kind of Hunter you despise!
仲間の苦しみに比べれば 私の誇りなど意味のないものだ。
The blow to my pride is nothing, measured against the suffering
my clan endured.
悪ぃが　俺には　お前みたいな 立派な動機は　ねえよ。
Sorry, but I have no noble cause.
えっ？ 俺の目的は　やっぱり金さ！
Huh? I'm just after money.
ウソをつくな。 ウソじゃ　ねえよ！
Don't lie! I'm not lying!
まさか　本当に金で この世の全てが買えるとでも 思ってるのか？
You really believe you can buy
everything with money?
買えるさ！　物は　もちろん 夢も　心も　人の命だって 金次第だ！
You bet! For the right price, you can buy not only
treasures, but dreams, hearts, and even people's lives!
なっ！　撤回しろ　レオリオ！
Take that back, Leorio!
クルタ族のことをいってるなら 許さんぞ！
If you're insulting the Kurta,
I won't forgive you.
なぜだ？　事実だぜ！
Why? I'm telling the truth.
金がありゃ 俺の友達は　死ななかった！
If I'd had money, my friend
wouldn't have died!
病気か？
An illness?
決して 治らない病気じゃなかった。
It was a treatable disease...
俺は単純だからな！ 医者になろうと思ったぜ！
I was naïve! I thought I could become a doctor...
ダチと同じ病気の子供を治して 「金なんか　いらねえ」って
I wanted to cure kids who have
the same disease, and be able to tell them
it was free of charge!
その子の親にいってやるのが 俺の夢だった。
Then I could have told his parents, too. That was my dream...
笑い話だぜ！
What a joke.
そんな医者になるためには さらに見たこともねえ 大金がいるそうだ！
Turns out that to become a doctor, you need even more money!
分かったか！　金　金　金だ！ 俺は　金が欲しいんだよ！
Got it? The world runs on money... So I want money!
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。 ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。 お先に　クラピカ！
See you at the goal, Kurapika.
おっさん　先　行くぜ！
Catch you later, old timer.
おっさんじゃ　ねえ！　俺は　まだ お前らと同じ１０歳代だ！
I'm not old! I'm a teenager, just like you guys!
えっ！ ウソ!?
Huh? No way!
も…　もう　無理だぁ…。
Can't take another step...
げ…　限界だぜ…。
Th-This is it...
俺のペースに　ついて来るなんて 結構やるじゃん。
I'm impressed that you
can keep up with me.
そう？　エヘヘ！
Really?
っていうか みんなのペースが遅いんだな。
Or maybe it's just that
everyone else is too slow.
はあ　こんなんじゃ ハンター試験　楽勝かもな。
Man... The Hunter Exam is gonna be a breeze.
つまんねえの。
That's no fun.
ねぇ　キルアは　何で ハンターになりたいの？
Hey, why do you want to
become a Hunter?
俺？　別にハンターになんか なりたくないよ。
Me? I'm not really interested in
becoming a Hunter.
えっ？
Huh?
ものすごい難関だって いわれてるから 面白そうだと思っただけさ。
I heard the exam was supposed
to be really hard, so I thought it'd be fun.
けど　拍子抜けだな。
But this is disappointing.
ゴンは？
What about you?
俺はさ　親父がハンターなんだ。
Well, my dad's a Hunter.
で　俺も親父みたいなハンターに なりたいと思って。
So I want to become a Hunter, like my dad.
ふん 親父って　どんなハンター？
Hmm... What kind of Hunter is he?
分かんない。
I don't know.
プッ　アハハハ！ お前　それじゃ　変じゃん！
That's kinda weird.
そう？
Really?
だって　親父みたいになりたいのに 親父のこと分かんないなんてさ。
You want to be like your dad, but you don't know anything about him?
俺　生まれて　すぐ ミトさんに育てられたから 親父は写真でしか知らないんだ。
I was raised by Mito-san, so I've only seen my dad in pictures.
誰だよ　ミトさんって。
Who's Mito-san?
ミトおばさん。 はぁ。
Aunt Mito. Oh...
親父も１２歳の時に ハンター試験　受けたんだってさ！
When he was twelve,
my dad took the Hunter Exam.
合格して　ハンターになって そして　島を出て行った。
He passed and became a Hunter. Then he left the island.
俺を捨ててまで 夢中になったハンターって
I want to find out why he
chose to be a Hunter
どんなんだろうって。
over being with me.
出口だ！ 助かった！
The exit! Whew...
ようやく 薄暗い地下から　おさらばだ！
Finally, I can get out of this dark tunnel!
さて　ここまで　一体　何人が ついて来られたでしょうか…
Now, let's see how many made it this far.
ゴール！ ゴール！ アハハ！ アハハ！
Goal!
やった！　俺の勝ち！
Yay! I win.
何いってんだ！ 俺のほうが早かっただろ！
What are you talking about? I was faster...
俺だよ！ 俺だって！
I was. No, I was!
俺のほうが早かったんだから キルア　ごはん　おごって！
I was faster, so you have to buy dinner!
いいや　早かったのは俺だ！ お前が　飯おごれ！
Nope! I was faster. So you buy me dinner.
俺のほうが早かったもん！
But I was faster.
ねぇ　どっちが早かった？
Hey, who was faster?
そっか。
Oh...
じゃあ　俺が　キルアに ごはん　おごる！ えっ？
Then I'll buy you dinner.
代わりに　キルアが 俺に　ごはん　おごって！
Huh? Then you buy me dinner!
何だよ　それ。
I don't get it.
ねぇ　サトツさん ここが　２次試験会場なの？
Hey, Satotz-san. Is this where the Second Phase
of the exam takes place?
いいえ　まだまだ先ですよ。
No, we still have quite a way to go.
なんだ。
Oh...
やぁ！　クラピカ。
Hey, Kurapika!
あぁ　ここがゴールか？
Is this our destination?
違うってさ。
No, it isn't.
そうか…　霧が晴れて来たぞ。
I see. The fog is fading.
あっ　ホント？
Really?
ヌメーレ湿原 通称「詐欺師のねぐら」。
The Numere Wetlands, also known as Swindlers Swamp.
２次試験場へは　ここを通って 行かねばなりません。
We must cross these wetlands to
reach Phase Two of the exam.
この湿原にしかいない 奇怪な動物達。 その多くが人間をも欺いて 食料にしようとする
This place is home to many bizarre animals, many of them being cunning, insatiable creatures
狡猾で貪欲な生き物です。
who deceive humans and prey upon them.
十分　注意して ついて来てください。
Be very careful.
騙されると死にますよ。
If you let them fool you... ...you're dead.
待ってくれ！　あぁ！
Wait for me!
この湿原の生き物は
These wetland creatures will use
ありとあらゆる方法で 獲物を欺き　捕食しようとします。
every trick in the book to fool their prey.
標的を騙して食い物にする 生物達の生態系
An ecosystem in which creatures
obtain food through deceit...
「詐欺師のねぐら」と呼ばれる ゆえんです。
Hence the name Swindlers Swamp.
騙されることのないよう しっかり私の後を ついて来てください。
Stay very close to me so you won't be deceived.
ケッ　ふざけた話だぜ。
What a joke.
騙されるのが分かってて 騙されるわけねえだろ。
How can they fool us,
when we're expecting it?
騙されるな！
Don't let them fool you!
あっ？　だから　騙されねえって。
I just said that they can't.
だ…　騙されるな…。
D-Don't fall for it...
そいつは ウソをついている！
He's lying to you!
そいつは偽者だ！ 試験官じゃ　ない！
He's an impostor! He isn't an examiner...
俺が本物の試験官だ！
I'm the real examiner.
偽物？　どういうことだ？
An impostor? What's going on?
じゃあ　こいつは一体？
Then who is he?
これを見ろ！
Look at this...
うわっ　サトツさん　そっくり！
He looks just like Satotz-san!
ヌメーレ湿原に生息する 人面猿だ！
It's a Man-Faced Ape, one of the creatures
that dwell in the Numere Wetlands!
人面猿だぁ？
A Man-Faced Ape?
人面猿は新鮮な人肉を好む。
Man-Faced Apes love the taste
of fresh human flesh.
しかし　手足が細長く 非常に力が弱い。
However, their limbs are long and thin,
so they're quite weak.
そこで　自ら　人に化けて
That's why they disguise themselves as humans.
言葉巧みに 人間を湿原に連れ込み 他の生物と手を組んで食い殺す。
They trick humans into following them
into these wetlands, where they team up with other animals
to kill and devour them.
そいつは　ハンター試験に集まった 受験生を 一網打尽にする気だぞ！
He intends to trap every single applicant!
野郎…。
Bastard...
確かに　あの走り　とても 人間業とは思えなかったもんな。
He certainly doesn't walk like a human...
えっ？
Huh?
これで決定。
That settles it...
そっちが本物だね。
You're the real one.
え！ やっぱり本物なんだ！
What? He's the real examiner?
え？ キキ！　キキキ！　キキキ！
Huh?
試験官というのは
Examiners are Hunters
審査委員会から 依頼されたハンターが 無償で任務に就くもの。
selected by the committee to perform
this duty without pay.
我々が目指すハンターの 端くれともあろう者が あの程度の攻撃を 防げないわけないからね。
Any Hunter, bearing the title we seek, would have been able to block that attack.
褒め言葉として 受け取っておきましょう。
I shall take that as a compliment.
しかし　次からは いかなる理由でも 私への攻撃は 試験官への反逆行為とみなして
However, should you attack me again,
for any reason, I will report you for turning
on an examiner.
即　失格とします。
And you will be immediately disqualified.
いいですね。
Are we clear?
はいはい。
Sure.
自然の掟とはいえ エグいもんだぜ。
Nature really can be brutal to watch...
やはり　あの男も人面猿。
So he was a Man-Faced Ape, as well.
私を偽者扱いして 受験者を混乱させ 何人か 連れ去ろうとしたのでしょうね。
He was attempting to confuse
the applicants, to lure some of them away.
油断も隙もないな。 うん。
We cannot relax our guard. Yeah.
こうした命懸けの騙し合いが 日夜　行われているのです。
You will be encountering such
deception on a regular basis.
現に　何人かは騙されかけて 私を疑ったんじゃありませんか？
I believe that a number of you
い…　いやぁ。
were fooled into suspecting my identity?
よろしいですか？ この先　ヌメーレ湿原の中は 霧が深く 一度　この私を見失うと　まず ２次試験会場へ　たどり着くことは できないでしょう。
Do you understand? If you lose sight of me in
the Numere Wetlands fog, you will never reach the exam's Second Phase.
ご注意を。
Do bear that in mind.
では　まいりますよ ついて来てください。
Then let us be on our way. Please follow me.
チッ　またマラソンだぜ。
Tsk, another marathon.
しかも　今度は湿原だ。
And we're running through marsh this time.
足元が　ぬかるんでいる分 体力が奪われるぞ。
Running on wet ground requires more energy.
ようやく　長く暗い トンネルを抜けた受験者達
The applicants have finally escaped
the long, dark tunnel.
ここまで ３６名の受験者が脱落し 残り３６８名
Thus far, 36 candidates have
withdrawn from the exam, leaving 368 remaining applicants.
次なる試練は　ヌメーレ湿原 通称「詐欺師のねぐら」
Their next challenge is the Numere Wetlands, also known as Swindlers Swamp.
過酷なハンター試験は まだ続く
The brutal Hunter Exam continues.